## SVITLANA ZASTER

## Houston, TX 77057



linkedin.com/in/svitlana-zaster-77a9a06b



https://szaster.github.io/SZPortfolio/



szaster@protonmail.com



(832) 692-2564.

## SUMMARY

Experienced full stack coding camp graduate with extensive background in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, MySQL, MongoDB developing intuitive web applications from the ground up. Professional strengths include creative problem-solving, written and verbal communication, effective time management. Detail oriented with an analytical mind-set from 10+ years of experience in research, scientific programming and education. Adaptable, diligent, open-minded, creative and flexible. Excellent presentation, communication and organizational skills.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Wolfram Language, SQL with MySQL and MongoDB

Frameworks: React, Materialize, Bootstrap, jQuery, Express, Node

Other Tech: GitHub, GitKraken, Sequelize, Mongoose, LaTeX, Wolfram Mathematica

#### **EDUCATION**



The University of Texas at Austin

2020

Certificate: Full Stack Development Boot Camp



University of Houston

2017

Degree: PhD, Theoretical Physical Chemistry



National Technical University of Ukraine 'Kyiv Polytechnic Institute'

2004

Degree: Master's; Major: Physics, Education

#### **EXPERIENCE**



## Full Stack Web Developer

Mar 2020 - present

#### The University of Texas at Austin

- Wrote complex front end to backend applications with multiple models and data associations, implemented user authentication:
- Designed and developed responsive full stack web applications independently, and in a group setting;
- Mastered CLI and acquired extensive experience in browser-based technologies, server side deployment, databases and quality assurance.



#### Research Assistant

2008 - 2017

#### General Chemistry Instructor

2008 - 2010, 2020 - present

#### University of Houston

- built theoretical models of physical processes and performed scientific programming using Wolfram Language and Wolfram Mathematica;
- conducted weekly lectures and problem solving sessions to 50+ students;
- demonstrated techniques of the proper and safe laboratory equipment usage

# Л'n

## **AWARDS**

Best graduate student poster - Theoretical Chemistry Conference - Texas A&M University

2012